## **MAKI HIROSE**

Portfolio: makidesigner.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/makihirose</u>

Contact: maki@makidesigner.com | +81 50 5806 3669 | Kyoto, Japan (remote work)

#### **SUMMARY**

Project Manager with UX/UI design and coding skills.

Bilingual in English and Japanese.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

<u>UX/UI:</u> User Research, Market Research, User Interviewing, Affinity Mapping, User Persona, Information Architecture, User Flow, Sketching, Wireframing, Wireflow, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, Prototyping, Responsive Web Design, Design Systems, WCAG.

<u>Web Development:</u> React, JavaScript, CSS, JSX, HTML5, Bootstrap, jQuery, RESTful API, AJAX, AXIOS, JSON, Firebase, Node, Express, Sequelize, MySQL, Mongoose, MongoDB, Object-Relational Mapping, Handlebars, Heroku, JawsDB, mLab, Chrome DevTools, Git, GitHub, Agile, Scrum.

**Software:** VS Code, Figma, Sketch, XD, InVision, Photoshop, Lightroom, Bridge, After Effects, Premiere, Audition, Capture One, Photo Mechanic, Final Cut Pro, Logic Pro, Pro Tools, Word, Excel, Powerpoint, Azure DevOps, Jira, Monday, Adobe Experience Manager, Adobe Analytics, Command Line.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## <u>Tata Consultancy Services</u> - <u>Project Manager</u> - Tokyo, Japan

2022-Present

Project Manager of the UX/UI and service design team within the Digital Transformation Services division. Implemented Scrum framework into the team. Assigned to Insurance, Airline, Retail, Pharmaceutical and Steel industry accounts.

## RR Donnelley - Digital Lead - Tokyo, Japan

2021-2022

Assigned to the Morgan Stanley account, led and managed UX/UI design and web development projects. Transformed the cross functional team from Waterfall to Agile. Led APAC region Morgan Stanley website initiatives, generating over 20000 page views in the first five days of a high profile launch. Oversaw implementation and analyzed analytics data on websites.

## KPMG Ignition Tokyo - UX/UI Designer - Tokyo, Japan

2020-2021

Designing UX/UI for Machine Learning, AI, OCR and Blockchain platforms. Member of an award-winning Data Science team that develops cloud based enterprise solutions for KPMG Japan and Australia's Audit, Tax and Consulting services. Notable accomplishments include creating the first patented Excel Mapping UI and Machine Learning PDF Annotation UI in the world, and the first Design System within the KPMG network.

### Tangueray Gin - Product Designer - New York, USA

2016-2020

Redesigned TanquerayGin.com from scratch with the team and implemented incremental updates.

### Maybelline - Product Designer - New York, USA

2015-2016

Developed and launched Maybelline's new Fit Me! web app. Led the team through the visual design ideation.

# **MAKI HIROSE**

Page Two of Two

## Smirnoff - Product Designer - New York, USA

2012-2015

Executed Smirnoff.com's multiple redesign processes. Contributed to UX/UI and visual design.

## <u>Drive In Studios</u> - <u>Web Designer & Digital Imaging Specialist</u> - New York, USA

2007-2012

Designed and coded company and client sites. Supervised digital imaging and retouching on photoshoots.

Notable Clients: IBM, GE, Citi, Microsoft, Sony, Vodafone, Merck, AstraZeneca, Allianz and more.

## **EDUCATION**

New York University - New York, USA

UX Design for Emerging Technologies

Columbia University - New York, USA

Full Stack Web Development

New York University - New York, USA

Bachelors of Fine Art in Photography & Imaging

New York University Honors Scholar and Founders' Day Award Recipient - Tisch School of the Arts

St. Paul's School - London, UK

Japanese School in London (Hoshuko Saturday School) - London, UK

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO) - Scrum Alliance - New York, USA

Certified Scrum Master (CSM) - Scrum Alliance - New York, USA